

## Yu-Hung (Edward) Wu

Research Assistant at the institute of Information Science, Academia Sinica

in ()

edward.0726@gmail.com · https://marzear.github.io/ ·+886-975-298-256

I'm currently working at Academia Sinica as a research assistant. Passionate about Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning, and FinTech. Fully prepared to bring the pro-active learning attitude and unwavering dedication to pursuing professional growth that contribute to my exceptional academic and internship performance.

#### **Education**

National Taiwan University of Science and Technology (NTUST), Taipei Sep. 2017 – Jun. 2021 B.S., Computer Science and Information Engineering and also Major in Finance

- Overall GPA: 3.87 | CS Major GPA: 4.03 | Finance Major GPA: 3.86 | last 2 year GPA: 3.96
- Participated in the following under-graduate researches:
  - 1. BERT-Based Visual Question Answering (VQA) (Advised by Professor Kuan-Yu Chen)
  - 2. Video Activity Recognition in Sports Videos (Advised by Professor Bi-Ru Dai)
  - 3. High frequency trading (An interdisciplinary project, Advised by Professor Wei-Zhong Miao)
- I got 4<sup>th</sup> place in NTUST Computer Science Department Class 2021 Graduate Project Competition.

### **Work Experiences**

## Institute of Information Science, Academia Sinica, Taiwan Research Assistant

Jun. 2021 - Current

- Academia Sinica is the leading academic institution, and also the national academy in Taiwan.
- I'm working at the CKIP Lab, which goal is to construct research infrastructures with reusable resources for NLP.

# Industrial Technology Research Institute, Taiwan Machine Learning Engineer Internship

Jul. 2020 – Jun. 2021

- Invited to work in the institute due to my outstanding academic performance.
- Responsible for developing a Deep Reinforcement Learning (DRL)-based dialogue system. Our goal is to develop a new way (new agent) to solve dialogue policy learning (based on Q-Learning).
- I also developed an algorithm to evaluate the quality of every target-based conversations.

#### Teaching Assistant of Data Structures Course, NTUST

Aug. 2020 – Jan. 2021

- Become the teaching assistant in my advisor's course since I got "A+" in the course in 2018.
- Designed innovative programming assignments and helped students to solve the problems.

## Asia Pacific Machine Intelligence Company (AP-MIC), Taipei Software Engineer Internship

Sep. 2018 – Mar. 2020

- AP-MIC is a business partner with Google, which focuses on developing dialogue engines.
- I have participated in designing the structure of dialogue engines.
- Developed a COVID-19 chatbot, which had reached 82,000 conversation sessions.

#### **Technical Skills**

#### **Programming Languages**

Python – 3+ years C++, C – 2+ years

JavaScript, HTML, CSS – 2+ years

Node.js – <1 year

R - < 1 year

#### **Natural Language Processing**

BERT and its applications seq2seq applications

Transformer

Chinese Processing
Intent Classification

#### ML / Data Analysis Modules

RNN / CNN / GAN models

Tensorflow2, Keras

Numpy

Sklearn

**Pandas** 

#### **Full-stack Development**

Django

Flask

Angular 6

#### **Version Control**

Git

Docker

#### Other

Web Crawler

**Database Management** 

**API** Design

### **Competition Experiences**

Post Office Big Data Competition - Reached the Semifinals

Apr. 2019 - Jun. 2019

E-sun Tbrain NLP Competition – 5<sup>th</sup> place (409 participants in total)

Jun. 2020 – Aug. 2020

### **Leadership Experiences**

- Representative of computer science department in freshman orientation.
- Class representative in junior year.
- Team leader of course projects in full-stack development course, operating system course and software engineering course.

## Languages

- Mandarin (native)
- English (fluent)
- Japanese (novice)